<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>George Imura</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>http://georgeimura.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://georgeimura.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 17:04:14 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2015 17:04:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Retail Arbitrage - Golden Mario</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/mario.jpg&quot; align=&quot;middle&quot; style=&quot;width:304px;height:228px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Golden Mario, a gold spray-painted Nintendo ‘amiibo’ figure, sold out within minutes of being released on Walmart’s website.  The retail price for Golden Mario was $12.99 but did not last long.  After 8 minutes, the Nintendo figure was sold out.  Within minutes of being sold out on Walmart’s website, individuals started listing their pre-orders for $99.99 on eBay, which nets a profit spread of about $80 per figure. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Retail arbitrageurs around the United States bought as many figures as they could and resold them for enormous profits.  One popular eBay account listed 250 figures.  250 figures nets $21,750 for 8 minutes worth of work.  This translates to $326.25M per year if replicated as a full-time job over an entire year. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

This event was foreseen due to the popularity of Nintendo’s amiibo figures.  Nintendo can not produce amiibos as fast as market demands.  Similar amiibo figures, such as Meta Knight, Ike, and King Dedede, had similar sell-out times of minutes.  Currently, release dates for amiibos are never released to the public.  Therefore, arbitrageurs must scour the internet for days regarding news about the release of pre-orders.  Once pre-orders open, a blood bath ensues to punch in credit card numbers and shipping information. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Golden Mario is a strong case for the profitability of retail arbitrage.  Retail arbitrage is similar to market arbitrage.  Arbitrage is defined as purchasing an inefficiently priced asset and re-pricing that asset at market value which creates a profitability spread.  The Golden Mario was inefficiently priced at MSRP of $12.99 and re-priced at $99.99.  Therefore, retail arbitrageurs walked away with $87 of profit per figure. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

Golden mario will be in 3000 Walmart stores on 3/20.  Currently the price of a pre-ordered Golden Mario is $80 on eBay.  I am betting that the price will drop to $40 during release date due to the influx of supply from Walmart stores.


&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://georgeimura.com/2014/03/10/first-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://georgeimura.com/2014/03/10/first-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
